

Dedan Msafari

JavaScript, React and React Native Engineer, UI/UX Designer.

Komarock, Nairobi, 2823-00200, Kenya 0723275041 · <u>dedan.msafari@gmail.com</u>

Github, LinkedIn

Date / Place of birth 31/01/1998, Westlands, Nairobi

Nationality

Kenyan

Skills

Management Skills

Public Speaker

Quality Assuarance

Quick Learner

Front-End Development

UI/UX designer

React-Native Engineer

Hobbies

Playing Chess, Watching Ancient History movies Listening to philosophers of the middle ages listening to podcasts. Writing Stories.

Languages

English

Kiswahili

Profile

I am a **Front-end Engineer, React Native Engineer and UI/UX Designer** .I have profession experience building design mock-ups and prototypes using Figma. I have experience working with major front-end tools including the Jam-stack, graphQL and styling libraries i.e Material-UI and Styled components. I have a great foundation and core understanding of JavaScript. I have great working knowledge on React-Native, MongoDB and Firebase.

Employment History

UI/UX Developer, TouchInspiration, Nairobi

September 2021 — April 2022

I Designed based on client requirements, simple and intuitive user interfaces that enable users to achieve their desired goals. I was especially fond of seamless mobile designs.

Among my most memorable moments was where:-

- I Settled any client disputes in a professional and pleasant manner.
- I Worked to ensure a positive and stress-free user experience.

Consultant Software Engineer, Nairobi

April 2022 - July 2022

- Researched extensively on current technological trends in order to advice designers and engineers on best practices and technologies to use.
- I assisted developers in coming up with great designs for their mobile applications. This was done by correcting and redesigning previously sub optimal designs.
- Through constant communication i was able to improve my social skills,my understanding and attention to details, empathy levels and overall interpersonal skills.

Mobile Applications Engineer, Nairobi

August 2022 - February 2023

- Using my previous experience as a UI/UX Designer.I came up with simple and intuitive wire-frames, mock-ups and user stories for a social networking mobile app called Localize.

- Using React-Native I built the core of the First iteration of the mobile application using tools such as react-navigation and styled-components.
- -I learnt and implemented proper folder structuring and how to build reusable components to be used in multiple files. This resulted in easily readable and organized code.

Education

Bsc Computer Science, Egerton University, Nakuru

August 2016 — December 2020

Graduated with High Honors in my bachelors in Computer Science.I learnt alot about the IT industry and its eco-systems and with this knowledge i am ready to change the community using my technology skills.

Complete UI/UX Designer, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

January 2021 — March 2021

Learnt How to design User Interfaces with Figma. I was able to quickly move from Idea to design. I understood how to put users first while designing so as to bring about a seamless experience in client applications.

Javascript Mastery, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

April 2021 — June 2021

Learnt advanced patterns in Javascript, how to understand complex syntax and using functional programming to come up with great applications.

Complete React Developer, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

March 2022 — September 2022

- I gained extensive knowledge on the workings of the React Library.
- Through building a large-scale e-commerce web application, I learnt what it takes to build fast modular apps that are easy to modify and understand.
- I gained extensive knowledge and understanding of technologies such as Redux, styled-components and GraphQL.
- I gained an in depth understanding of both DRY and SOLID Principles while building react applications as well as an understanding of Design Patterns while architecturing them.

Attachment and Internships

Junior Software Engineer, Ongair, Nairobi

June 2019 — August 2019

under supervision from senior developers, I was able to implement features my most notable being adding a fully fledged button from its front-end to its back-end implementation on an existing Saas system. This was my first time gaining industry level experience and i learnt a lot. I worked with React Js and it was one of the best UI libraries i had ever seen.

References

ROSE MACHARIA from EACC(Ethics and Anti Corruption Comission) 0721345556

ELIZABETH KHAHOYA from HELB(Higher Education Loans Board) 0722959179

ROSE MWAVISWA from Miller and Miller Company 0721276431

Others

My Belief

January 2020 — Present

- I believe in Quality software that anyone can read.
- I believe that hiring empathetic software engineers is Key to the future of any tech company.
- I believe that working towards a certain goal with fellow team members who inspire you is Key to success.

Extra-curricular activities

Sports

June 2015 - Present

Running, Going for Nature walks,

Playing Football, Cycling and Archery.